RG 079:005, Department of Environmental Protection: Air, Waste and Water
Connecticut State Library
Department of Environmental Protection air waste and water records
1920-2013
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Dept. of Environmental Proteection
278.5 cubic feet
Air, Waste and Water records include: Deputy Commissioner; Planning and Standards; Bureau of Water Management; Bureau of Air Management; Inland Water Resources.
RG079_005
Multiple
Historical Note
With the creation of the Department of Environmental Protection in 1971, the Environmental Quality Division was given the mission of abating the pollution of the water, air and land of the state.1 Now known as the Bureau of Air, Waste and Water, this part of the Dept. of Environmental Protection has always been based on media (transport of pollutants, i.e. water and air) and business (source of pollutants, i.e. waste, pesticides, etc.). The functions of permitting, inspection, enforcement, and monitoring have been subsets of the primary structure.2
See also the.
Endnotes
1Press release, November 22, 1971, RG 079:001, Department of Ennvironmental Protection, Commissioner Arthur J. Rocque, Jr., Accession 2005-009, Organizational Evaluation, Box 6, Folder "First DEP Org Dan Lufkin Documents".
2Untitled and undated document, RG 079:001, Ennvironmental Protection, Commissioner Arthur J. Rocque, Jr., Accession 2005-009, Organizational Evaluation, Box 6, Folder "Historic Org Charts".
Scope and Content
Included here are records from the Deputy Commissioner, 1972-2004; Planning and Standards, 1970-1973; Bureau of Water Management, 1920-1979 that includes records from the Permitting, Enforcement, and Remediation Division; Bureau of Air Management, 1975-1992; and Inland Water Resources, 1939-2013 that includes records from the New England River Basins Commission, 1966-1975, the Connecticut Soil Advisory Committee, 1948-1974, 8 volumes of survey notes of Connecticut waterways, 1939-1941, and 3 dvds of the Municipal Inland Wetland Commissioners Training Program, 2007-2013.
Arrangement
Series numbers have been assigned within RG 079 in its entirety and therefore the series described here are not numbered consecutively.
Series 5. Deputy Commissioner, 1972-2004, 53 cubic feet
Eckardt C. Beck
Administrative Files, 1972-1985, Accession: 1988-023, 9 cubic feet
Melvin J. Schneidermeyer, 1975-1979
Accession: 1988-021, Subject Files, 1975-1979, 7 cubic feet
Accession: 1988-027 (part), Subject Files, 1975-1979, 2 cubic feet
Accession: 1988-031, Subject Files, 1975-1979, 4 cubic feet
John W. Anderson
Program Files, 1972-1986, Accession: 1989-059, 21 cubic feet
Robert A. Moore, 1988-1995
Accession: 1996-010, Budget and Thomas Commission Recommendation Files, 1990-1995, 2 cubic feet
Accession: 1997-023, Subject Files, 1988-1994, 3 cubic feet
Jane K. Stahl, 1997-2004
Accession: 2005-018, Subject Files, 1997-2004, 5 cubic feet
Series 11. Planning and Standards, 1970-1973, Accession: 1988-027 (part), 19 cubic feet
Series 14. Bureau of Water Management, 1920-1979
Permitting, Enforcement, and Remediation Division, 1928-1979, bulk 1969-1977
Accession: 1997-050, Correspondence Files, 145 cubic feet
Accession: 1997-051, Reports, 35 cubic feet
Ansonia Water Company, 1920, Accession: 1999-016, 0.25 cubic feet
Series 15. Bureau of Air Management, 1975-1992
Accession: 1998-037, Director's Subject Files, 1975-1987, 1 cubic foot
Accession: 1993-145, Hearings, 1988-1992, 23 cubic feet
Series 25. Inland Water Resources, 1939-2013
Accession: 1998-038, Commissions and Committee Records, 1939-1975, 2 cubic feet
Accession: 2014-036, Municipal Inland Wetland Commissioners Training Program, 2007-2013, 0.25 cubic feet
Related Material
Additional Department of Environmental Protection records can be found in:
RG 079:001, Central Office
RG 079:004, Aerial photographs, see the.
RG 079:016, Natural Resources and Outdoor Recreation
RG 079:018, Office of Indian Affairs
As well in these predecessor departments, boards, and commissions:
RG 079:003, Board of Fisheries and Game
RG 079:017, State Park and Forest Commission
RG 079:022, Forestry Department
RG 079:023, Water Resources Commission
RG 079:026, State Harbor Commissioners for New Haven Harbor
Other record groups:
RG 002:29, General Assembly Task Forces, Environment Committee Task Forces
RG 005, Office of the Governor contain files about the Department of Environmental Protection and its predecessors.
RG 015, Office of Policy and Management for records of grant programs transferred out of the Department of Agriculture.
RG 089, Department of Transportation contains the major statewide areil photographic surveys.
RG 098, Department of Agriculture
Index Terms
Organizations:
Connecticut. Dept. of Environmental Protection; Connecticut. Bureau of Water Mangement; Connecticut. Bureau of Air Management
Persons:
Beck, Eckhart C; Schneidermeyer, Melvin J; Anderson, John W; Moore, Robert A; Stahl, Jane K
Subjects:
Air -- Pollution -- Connecticut; Air quality management -- Connecticut; Connecticut. Bureau of Air Management -- Records and correspondence; Connecticut. Bureau of Water Management -- Records and correspondence; Connecticut. Dept. of Environmental Protection -- Records and correspondence; Environmental protection -- Connecticut; Groundwater -- Pollution -- Connecticut; Groundwater -- Quality -- Connecticut; Water resources development -- Connecticut
Document Types:
Correspondence; Minutes; Reports; DVDs
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Series 5. Deputy Commissioner, 1972-2004
  - Eckardt C. Beck, 1972-1985
    - Administrative Files, 1972-1985; 1988-023
      - Bluff Point (Box 1)
      - Candlewood Lake (Box 1)
      - Connecticut Inland Wetlands (Box 1)
      - Lake Waramaug (Box 1)
      - Meetings of Health Directors and Chief Sanitarians, 1974 September 18 (Box 1)
      - Petitions (Box 1)
      - Press-Water (Box 1)
      - Proposed Consent Agreement (Box 1)
      - Proposals (Box 1)
      - Sewage Disposal (Box 1)
      - Solid Waste Management (Box 1)
      - Support-Endorsement Letters (Box 1)
      - Transportation (Box 1)
      - Water (Box 1)
      - Water Compliance (Box 1)
      - Air Compliance 1 (Box 2)
      - Air Compliance 2 (Box 2)
      - Air Compliance Unit (Box 2)
      - Air Pollution 1 (Box 2)
      - Air Pollution 2 (Box 2)
      - Bills (Box 2)
      - Coal Conversion Task Force 1 (Box 2)
      - Coal Conversion Task Force 2 (Box 2)
      - Coal Conservation Task Force 3 (Box 2)
      - Complex Sources (Box 2)
      - Environmental Impact Statements Reviews (Box 2)
      - Legislative Progress Reports (Box 2)
      - Planning and Research I (Box 2)
      - Planning and Research II (Box 2)
      - Planning and Research III (Box 2)
      - Planning and Research IV (Box 2)
      - Press-Pesticides (Box 2)
      - Sulfur Oxide Briefing (Box 2)
      - Bridgeport (Box 3)
      - Consent Agreements (Box 3)
      - D’Addario Asphalt Plant, Milford (Box 3)
      - Milford Solid Waste Disposal (Box 3)
      - New Britain/Stanley Pac (Box 3)
      - Noise (Box 3)
      - Pesticide Compliance I (Box 3)
      - Pesticide Compliance II (Box 3)
      - Press-Solid Waste (Box 3)
      - Radiation Compliance (Box 3)
      - Solid Waste Management I (Box 3)
      - Solid Waste Management II (Box 3)
      - Solid Waste I (Box 3)
      - Solid Waste II (Box 3)
      - Testimony NEU I (Box 3)
      - Testimony NEU II (Box 3)
      - CRRA Municipal Guidelines (Box 3)
      - Civil Penalty Enforcement Package (CPEP) (Box 4)
      - CPEP Weekly Schedules (Box 4)
      - McKinsey Contract (Box 4)
      - CPEP Correspondence (Box 4)
      - Reviews, Reports and Charts (Box 4)
      - Memoranda CPEP (Box 4)
      - Data Processing (Box 4)
      - Finance and Control (Box 4)
      - Directors Meeting (Box 4)
      - DEP-Environmental Quality (Box 4)
      - EPA-Boston (Box 4)
      - Governor’s Office (Box 4)
      - Memos to Governor Grasso (Box 4)
      - Gas Coupons (Box 4)
      - Information (Box 4)
      - Legal and Governmental Affairs (Box 4)
      - Legislation (Box 4)
      - News Releases (Box 4)
      - Correspondence (Box 4)
      - Memos to the Commissioner (Box 4)
      - Office of the Commissioner (Box 4)
      - Personnel (Box 4)
      - Air Compliance Monthly Reports (Box 5)
      - Air Compliance (Box 5)
      - Air Quality (Box 5)
      - Air Pollution I (Box 5)
      - Air Pollution II (Box 5)
      - Air Pollution III (Box 5)
      - Air Pollution IV (Box 5)
      - Incoming Mail re: NEU (Box 5)
      - Letters to ECB, NEU copies (Box 5)
      - NEU (Box 5)
      - NEU Exhibits (Box 5)
      - Northeast Utilities Fuel Reports (Box 5)
      - Northeast Utilities (Box 5)
      - Oil Company Files (Box 5)
      - Open Burning Guidelines (Box 5)
      - Press-Air (Box 5)
      - Public Testimony (Box 5)
      - Yale-New Haven (Box 5)
      - DEP Exhibits I (Box 6)
      - DEP Exhibits II (Box 6)
      - DEP Exhibits III (Box 6)
      - Enforcement Bill and DEP Suggested Changes (Box 6)
      - Enforcement Bill I (Box 6)
      - Enforcement Bill II (Box 6)
      - Interdepartmental Advisory Board (Minutes) (Box 6)
      - Jules Mirabel File-GE (Box 6)
      - Solid Waste I (Box 6)
      - Solid Waste II (Box 6)
      - Solid Waste III (Box 6)
      - SW I (Box 6)
      - SW II (Box 6)
      - Solid Waste Management I (Box 6)
      - Solid Waste Management II (Box 6)
      - Solid Waste Projects (Box 6)
      - Automobiles-DEP I (Box 7)
      - Automobiles-DEP II (Box 7)
      - Background Materials-Refineries (Box 7)
      - Boston Materials Meeting with Dr. C. Smith (Box 7)
      - Budget I (Box 7)
      - Budget II (Box 7)
      - Business Office I (Box 7)
      - Business Office II (Box 7)
      - Consultant Contract (Box 7)
      - Energy I (Box 7)
      - Energy II (Box 7)
      - Energy Information (Box 7)
      - Energy News clippings (Box 7)
      - Energy News Releases (Box 7)
      - Energy Report-Joseph Wilson, Sr. (Box 7)
      - Environmental Advisory Committee (Box 7)
      - Gulf Letter (Box 7)
      - Matrix (Box 7)
      - Oil (Box 7)
      - Oil Consumption (Box 7)
      - Oil Development (Box 7)
      - Refinement Supply and Demand Analysis (Box 7)
      - Refineries (Box 7)
      - Refinery Consultants (Box 7)
      - Refinery Agenda (Box 7)
      - Refinery Impact Report I and II (Box 7)
      - Refinery Task Force Request for Proposal (RFP) (Box 7)
      - Application of NEU, Official File (Box 8)
      - Application of NEU, Personal Notes (Box 8)
      - Candlewood Lake (Box 8)
      - Connecticut Magazine Article (Box 8)
      - DEP Exhibits (Box 8)
      - ECB Personnel (Box 8)
      - Emergency Variance (Box 8)
      - Environmental Quality I (Box 8)
      - Environmental Quality II (Box 8)
      - Legal Memoranda (Box 8)
      - NEU Exhibits-Copies (Box 8)
      - NEU Exhibits (Box 8)
      - Notice of Reconvened Hearing, June 6, 1974 (Box 8)
      - Northeast (Box 8)
      - Office of the Deputy Commissioner (Box 8)
      - Water Compliance I (Box 8)
      - Water Compliance II (Box 8)
      - Water Injunctions I (Box 8)
      - Water Injunctions II (Box 8)
      - Water Quality Standards I (Box 8)
      - Water Quality Standards II (Box 8)
      - Altobell: Correspondence (Box 9)
      - Horace Brown Meeting (Box 9)
      - Burns Correspondence (Box 9)
      - Comprehensive Grant Report (Box 9)
      - Comprehensive Employment and Training Grant (Box 9)
      - DEP Training Programs (Box 9)
      - General Grant Regulations (Box 9)
      - Integrated Development Projects (Box 9)
      - I-291 Reviews (Box 9)
      - Labor Funds (Box 9)
      - Permit Review Committee (Box 9)
      - Planning and Research I (Box 9)
      - Planning and Research II (Box 9)
      - Public Information (Box 9)
      - Refinery Proposals (Box 9)
      - Reports (Box 9)
      - Resumes (Box 9)
      - Solid Waste Management (Box 9)
      - Transportation I (Box 9)
      - Transportation II (Box 9)
      - Transportation Control Strategies (Box 9)
      - WIN Funds (Box 9)
  - Melvin J. Schneidermeyer, 1975-1979
    - Subject Files, 1975-1979; 1988-021
      - Water Resources 1-6 (Box 15-1)
      - Water Compliance 16 (Box 15-1)
      - Chronological File (Box 15-2)
        - 1978 September 20 - 1979 October 31 (Box 15-2)
        - 1975 May 23 - 1976 August 31 (Box 15-2)
        - 1977 August 8 - 1978 September 29 (Box 15-2)
        - 1977 April 1 - August 10 (Box 15-2)
      - Rivers (Box 15-3)
        - Recreational Rivers - Congressional Designation. (Box 15-3)
        - Low-head Hydra (Box 15-3)
        - Wetlands (Box 15-3)
        - Rivers Advisory Council (Box 15-3)
        - Information & Education Information (Box 15-3)
        - State River Management (Box 15-3)
        - Recreational River Conference (Box 15-3)
        - Wild & Scenic & Recreational Rivers (Box 15-3)
        - Odd & End Brochures (Box 15-3)
        - In-stream Flow Policies (Box 15-3)
        - Connecticut Studies (Box 15-3)
        - Wild & Scenic & Recreational River (Federal Actions) (Box 15-3)
        - Wild & Scenic & Recreational River (State Actions) (Box 15-3)
        - Hydropower Development (Box 15-3)
        - Local Actions (Box 15-3)
        - Wild & Scenic & Recreational River (Bibliography) (Box 15-3)
        - Federal Studies & Findings (Box 15-3)
        - Wild & Scenic & Recreational River (Case Studies) (Box 15-3)
        - Wild & Scenic & Recreational River (Legislation) (Box 15-3)
        - Reports 7 Studies (Box 15-3)
        - Greenline Parks (Box 15-3)
        - Miscellaneous River Material (Box 15-3)
        - Legislation (Box 15-3)
      - Water Compliance 1-9 (Box 15-4)
      - Solid Waste 1-5 (Box 15-5)
      - Bureau of Administration 1-5 (Box 15-6)
      - Air Compliance 1-9 (Box 15-7)
    - Subject Files, 1975-1979; 1988-027 (part)
      - 208 Program 1-7 (Box 15-8)
      - Personnel 1-5 (Box 15-9)
      - Water Resources 7 (Box 15-9)
    - Subject Files, 1975-1979; 1988-031
      - Coastal Area Management 1-7 (Box 29-1)
      - Coastal Zone Management (Box 29-1)
      - Personnel (Box 29-1)
      - Coastal Area Management 8-12 (Box 29-2)
      - Water Compliance 10-15 (Box 29-3)
      - Air Compliance 10-15 (Box 29-4)
  - John W. Anderson, 1972-1986
    - Program Files, 1972-1986; 1989-059
      - Air Compliance, 1975-1979 (Box 1)
      - Air Compliance, 1975-1982 (Box 2)
      - Hazardous Waste and Water Resources, 1979-1985 (Box 3)
      - Acid Rain, 1981-1985 (Box 4)
      - Water Compliance, Hazardous Waste, Radiation, and Water Resources, 1972-1985 (Box 5)
      - Hazardous Waste, 1973-1985 (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous, 1982-1985 (Box 7)
      - Miscellaneous, 1975-1985 (Box 8)
      - CAM, 1971-1985 (Box 9)
      - Telephone Packages, 1984-1985 (Box 10)
      - Solid Waste, Governor’s Office, 1981-1985 (Box 11)
      - Water Compliance and Telephone Packages, 1978-1985 (Box 12)
      - Telephone Packages, Monthly Status, and Waste Oil Regulations, 1983-1986 (Box 13)
      - Water Compliance and Solid Waste, 1981-1985 (Box 14)
      - Air Compiance, 1983-1985 (Box 15)
      - Solid Waste, Legislation, and Reorganization, 1975-1984 (Box 16)
      - Solid Waste, 1981-1985 (Box 17)
      - Information and Education, Business, Budget, and C&P, 1981-1985 (Box 18)
      - Solvence Recovery, 1978-1985 (Box 19)
      - Miscellaneous, 1971-1980 (Box 20)
      - Air Compliance, 1976-1979 (Box 21)
  - Robert A. Moore, 1988-1995
    - Budget and Thomas Commission Recommendation Files, 1990-1995; 1996-010 (Box 1-2)
      Unarranged.
    - Subject Files, 1988-1994; 1997-023
      - RFP-Permit Processing Review Project, 1991-1992 (Box 1)
      - Published Reports (Box 1)
      - Thomas Commission Recommendations, 1990-1992 (Box 2)
      - Gubernatorial Transition, 1990 (includes critical issues) (Box 2)
      - Low-level Radioactive Waste Management Regulations, 1991 (Box 2)
      - Reorganization-DEP and Dept. of Agriculture, 1989-1992 (Box 2)
      - Fees, 1989-1990 (Box 3)
      - Memo of understanding, DEP/DOT, 1988 July (Box 3)
      - Hazardous Material Transportation Act Grant Program (Box 3)
      - Land, 1988 (Box 3)
      - Regional Capitol Development Program, 1993-1994 (Box 3)
        Includes applications, correspondence, and reviews.
      - Right of Way Pesticide Plans (Box 3)
      - State Emergency Response Commission, 1991-1993 (Box 3)
        Includes correspondence, quarterly reports, meeting minutes, letters of appointment, toxic release inventories, copies of EPA and other reports.
  - Jane K. Stahl, 1997-2004
    - Subject Files, 1997-2004; 2005-018
      - Adjudications, 1997-2000 (Box 1)
      - AG's correspondence, 2000-2002 (Box 1)
      - Air (Box 1)
        - Clear Skies Initiative, 2002 (Box 1)
        - Contractors Supply, 2000 (Box 1)
        - Fedus Associates, 1998-1999 (Box 1)
        - NESCAUM, 1998-1999 (Box 1)
        - Nox SIP, 1998-2000 (Box 1)
        - Quinnipiac Energy, 2000-2001 (Box 1)
        - SEMPRA, 1999 (Box 1)
        - Title V Operating Permits Program, 2002 (Box 1)
      - Audits, 1996-1999 (Box 1)
      - Barn Island Wildlife Management Area, 2003 (Box 1)
      - CEQ – Council on Environmental Quality, 2002 (Box 1)
      - Correspondence-Jane K. Stahl (Box 1)
      - CRRA (Box 1)
        - Hartford Landfill, 1999-2000 (Box 1)
        - Mid Conn (Final Decision), 1999 (Box 1)
        - Mid Conn Arguments, 1999 (Box 1)
        - Shelton Landfill, 1997-2000 (Box 1)
      - CT Juvenile Training School, 1999-2000 (Box 2)
      - CT River American Heritage River Project, 1998-1999 (Box 2)
      - DEP (Box 2)
        - Case Conclusion Data Sheet, 1997-1999 (Box 2)
        - Delegation of Authority, 1987-2004 (Box 2)
        - Personnel Issues, 1998-2002 (Box 2)
        - Record Retention, 2000 (Box 2)
      - EHHI (Environment & Human Health Inc.), 1998 (Box 2)
      - Electric Reconstructing, 1997-1998 (Box 2)
      - Ensign Bickford, 1999-2000 (Box 2)
      - Env. Par t.Agree. between CT DEP & EPA, 1998-1999 (Box 2)
      - Environmental Compliance in CT, 1998-2000 (Box 2)
      - Environmental Enforcement, 1998-2000 (Box 2)
      - EPA (Box 3)
        - Enforcement and Compliance Assistance, 1998 (Box 3)
        - Joint State Agreement to Pursue Regulatory (Box 3)
        - Chemical Industry Audit, 1997-1998 (Box 3)
        - Funding – NEEP (Northeast Environmental (Box 3)
        - Performance Partnership Agreement, 1999 (Box 3)
      - Exide/INCO Clean Up (Town of Fairfield), 1998-1999 (Box 3)
      - Federal Grant Applica. re Civil Rights Complaints, 1998 (Box 3)
      - Franklin Mushroom Farm, 2002 (Box 3)
      - Information Technology, 1997 (Box 3)
      - International Paper, 1997-1999 (Box 3)
      - Iroquois Settlement Fund Program, 1999 (Box 3)
      - Islander East, 2002-2003 (Box 3)
      - Long Wharf Mall, 1999 (Box 3)
      - MDC Compost & Portland, 1998-2000 (Box 3)
      - MOU – Dominion Nuclear (Millstone), 2002 (Box 3)
      - Naval Undersea Warfare Center, 1998 (Box 3)
      - NEGC (Box 3)
        - Mercury Resolution (Box 3)
        - Climate Change Action Plan, 2001 (Box 3)
        - Comm. On the Env., 2000-2002 (Box 3)
      - NEGIP (N. Eng. Env. Goals &Indicators Part., 1998-1999 (Box 3)
      - NEJAC (Box 3)
        - Emissions Trading Resolution (Box 3)
        - Fish Consumption Report, 2002 (Box 3)
        - Cumulative Risk, 2002 (Box 3)
      - New Haven Development, 1998 (Box 3)
      - New London Development Corporation – (4 folders), 1997-1999 (Box 4)
      - Northeast Lamp Recycling, 1999-2000 (Box 4)
      - Northeast Utilities, 1998-2003 (Box 4)
      - Norwich Hospital, 1991-1994 (Box 4)
      - O.N.E./C.H.A.N.E., Inc., 1998-2002 (Box 4)
      - OEM (Office of Emergency Management) (Box 4)
      - OEPC (Office of Enforcement Policy & Coordination), 1999 (Box 4)
      - Oil Fuel Emergency New Haven & Bridgeport, 2000 (Box 4)
      - OLISP – Clinton Harbor Dredging, 2000-2001 (Box 4)
      - OPSAIL, 2000-1999 (Box 4)
      - Permit Timeframe Regulations, 1997-1999 (Box 4)
      - Personnel Development Advisory Committee, 1997-1998 (Box 4)
      - PPA – FY 1998-1999 (Box 4)
      - PPA – FY 2000-2001 (Box 4)
      - RACT (Reasonably Available Control Technology), 1998 (Box 4)
      - Raymark Industries, Stratford, 1999-2000 (Box 4)
      - Regulation Approval Procedures, 1999 (Box 4)
      - Route 11, 1998 (Box 4)
      - RPO (Regional Planning Organizations), 1999 (Box 4)
      - S & H Industries, 1998 (Box 4)
      - Safety Kleen, 1998 (Box 4)
      - SEBMAP Realty, 2000 (Box 4)
      - SEP (Supplemental Environmental Projects), 2000 (Box 4)
      - SIC Prototype Reactor Plant – Windsor, 1996-1997 (Box 4)
      - STEJ (State Tribal Grant USEPA), 1999 (Box 4)
      - Super 7, 1998 (Box 4)
      - SWEP (Society of Women Env. Professionals), 1999 (Box 4)
      - Testimony Water Resources & Environment Regarding (Box 4)
      - Testimony – DEP Enforcement Programs, 1998 (Box 4)
      - Transenergie U.S. Ltd., 2000-2001 (Box 4)
      - Tweed New Haven Airport, 2002 (Box 4)
      - UARCO, Inc., 1997 (Box 5)
      - UCONN – Football Field Study, 1995-2001 (Box 5)
      - Uniroyal Chemical Co., Naugatuck, 1999 (Box 5)
      - US Commission on Ocean Policy remarks by (Box 5)
      - US Navy – Submarine Realignment, 1991-1995 (Box 5)
      - Waste (Box 5)
        - AUTOFLUFF, 1999 (Box 5)
        - Lighting Services, Inc., 2001 (Box 5)
        - Manchester Landfill, 1999 (Box 5)
        - Monthly Enforcement Action Meeting (Box 5)
        - NEMA (National Electrical Mfg Assoc), 1999-2000 (Box 5)
        - New Milford Landfill, 1998 (Box 5)
        - Sound Manufacturing, 2001 (Box 5)
        - SWMP (Solid Waste Management Plan), 1998-2001 (Box 5)
        - Underground Storage Tanks, 1998-2001 (Box 5)
        - Wheelabrator, 1997-2000 (Box 5)
        - Yaworski Landfill, 2001 (Box 5)
      - Water (Box 5)
        - Aquifer Protection, 1998-2000 (Box 5)
        - Brookfield, Town of, 1999-2000 (Box 5)
        - Cadlerock Properties v. DEP, 2001 (Box 5)
        - Clinton Town of, 2000-2001 (Box 5)
        - Combined Sewer Overflow Program CSO, 2001 (Box 5)
        - Cornwall (Housatonic River), 1999 (Box 5)
        - Floodplain Management, 1999 (Box 5)
        - Islander East (Box 5)
        - Jewett City WPC/Lisbon Landing, 2000 (Box 5)
        - Middlebury, Town of, 1999-2002 (Box 5)
        - Norwalk City of, 1995-2002 (Box 5)
        - Old Saybrook, 2001-2002 (Box 5)
        - PDC El Paso – Milford, 1998-2000 (Box 5)
        - Quarry Pond, Greenwich, 2000 (Box 5)
        - Rand Whitney Containerboard, 2000-2001 (Box 5)
        - Remediation Proj. Pending (Box 5)
        - Unionville Water Co., 1999 (Box 5)
        - Vernon Town of, 2000 (Box 5)
        - Waterbury Wastewater Treatment Plant, 1998 (Box 5)
        - Waterford Town of, 1997 (Box 5)
      - Waterbury Republican, 1998-1999 (Box 5)
      - Y2K, 1999 (Box 5)
- Series 11. Planning and Standards, 1970-1973; 1988-027 (part)
  - Part I: Civil Defense and Oil Spills (Box 21-1)
    - Civil Defense: Annex B (Communications) (Box 21-1)
    - Civil Defense: Annex D (Police) (Box 21-1)
    - Civil Defense: Annex E (Emergency Welfare) (Box 21-1)
    - Civil Defense: Annex F (Engineering) (Box 21-1)
    - Civil Defense: Annex F (Transportation) (Box 21-1)
    - Civil Defense: Annex H (Radiological Defense) (Box 21-1)
    - Civil Defense: Annex J&L (Warden and Rescue) (Box 21-1)
    - Civil Defense: Annex K (Fire) (Box 21-1)
    - Civil Defense: Annex M (Manpower) (Box 21-1)
    - Civil Defense: Annex N (Administration) (Box 21-1)
    - Civil Defense: Annex O (Health, Medical and Mortuary) (Box 21-1)
    - Civil Defense: Annex P (Economic Requirements and Controls) (Box 21-1)